You know his name
Jason Bourne is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Paul Greengrass.
The most dangerous former operative of the CIA is drawn out of
hiding to uncover hidden truths about his past.
Jason Bourne, played by Matt Damon.
CIA Director Robert Dewey, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Heather Lee, played by Alicia Vikander.
Asset, played by Vincent Cassel.
Nicky Parsons, played by Julia Stiles.
Aaron Kalloor, played by Riz Ahmed.
Jason Bourne is a 2016 American action thriller film co-produced and directed by
Paul Greengrass, who co-wrote the script with Christopher Rouse.
It is the fifth installment of the Bourne film series and a
direct sequel to The Bourne Ultimatum (2007).
Matt Damon reprises his role as the main character, former CIA
assassin Jason Bourne, in addition to co-producing the film.
In addition, the film stars Tommy Lee Jones, Alicia Vikander, Vincent Cassel, Riz Ahmed, Ato
Essandoh, Scott Shepherd, with Julia Stiles reprising her role as Nicky Parsons.
The character Aaron Cross, from The Bourne Legacy (2012), does not appear in the film because director Greengrass wanted to focus
on the title character, and because actor Jeremy Renner was unable to participate due to scheduling conflicts.
In Jason Bourne, Bourne remains on the run from CIA hit squads as he tries to uncover hidden truths about his father, while
CIA director Robert Dewey (Jones) orders the head of cyber-security Heather Lee (Vikander) to hunt him down.
Principal photography on the film commenced on September 8, 2015.
Jason Bourne premiered in London on July 11, 2016, and
was theatrically released in the U.S.
by Universal Pictures on July 29, 2016.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $415 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of assassin, central
intelligence agency (cia), amnesia, casino, chase.
The tone is intense.